let's discuss the solution for our
newest iron law quiz we have 50 billion
instructions with different cpis so
clearly we need to use our newest
version of the iron law of performance
execution time is a sum of number of
instructions of a particular type times
the CPI for that type in this case it's
10 * 10 9th which is 10 billion * 4 for
branches plus 15 billion * 2 for loads
plus 5 billion * 3 for stores and we
said the remaining instructions are
integer ad instructions we have 30
billion instructions here so 20 billion
are integer ads at CPI of 1 and all of
that times the clock cycle time which is
1 over 4 * 10 the 9th again 4 GHz is the
clock frequency see the clock cycle time
is one over that now let's do the math
here this is 40 + 30 + 15 + 20 * 10 9th
/ 4 * 10 to the 9th so 10 to the 9th can
be crossed out and we get 105 over 4
which amounts to
26.25 so this is how long it takes to
run this 50 billion instructions at 4 G
GHz assuming these cpis and this
distribution of instructions